Hasan G. Jaffal

Project Manager / Software Development Expert

Beirut, Lebanon - 00961 3 926130 - jaftalks@icloud.com - jaftalks.com

PROFILE

Over ten years experience in the software development field with extensive experience in project management and systems design and architecture.

My extensive experience, first as a software engineer on multiple platforms and domains, then as software architect and then project manager of software development projects, equipped me with a large arsenal of tools and approaches and gave me an excellent understanding of software practices and architecture and a long experience in database design, data migration and data visualization.

I have worked on software projects in the private and the public sectors in Africa and the Middle East and have worked on international software projects across a range of industries including cadaster, urban planning, tourism, violence risk mitigation and elections planning and management.

I have worked on ICT for development projects with International bodies including UNDP, NDI, IFES, DAI and local NGOs including LADE and LPHU.

Driven by the passion to empower civil society organizations in Lebanon, I volunteer to help several NGOs building their online presence and making use of technology in their daily work. I am on the board of the Project Management Institute - Lebanon Chapter NGO and an active member of the community.

SKILLS

- Project Management PMP Business Analysis Requirements
 Management Communication Presentation ICT for Development
- Software Architecture and Development, Web Development, Open Source, Mobile Development, Content Management Systems
- Online Presence Building Data Visualization Mapping and GIS
- Database Design and Data Migration
- MS Project MS Office Apple iWorks
- Graphics: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Flash, Adobe Animate,
- Languages: Arabic, English, French

EXPERIENCE

ArabiaGIS, Lebanon

Project Manager and Software Development Expert — 2012–Present

- Managing medium to large scale international software projects.
- Prepare proposals and request for proposals for ICT projects.
- Analyze and collect user, business, and, system requirements and create mockups, visualize and create prototypes.
- Prepare and Present analysis, and training documentation.
- Design and model software architecture including open source and proprietary software
- Providing consultancy in Software Architecture and Design and Coding best practices.

Senior Software Developer and Solution Architect — 2008 - 2012

- Scheduling, leading, achieving and following up projects.
- Performing business, functional and technical analysis and writing technical documentation.
- Developing Web, Mobile and GIS applications using <u>ASP.NET</u>, PHP, JAVA, MVC, Silverlight, WPF, ESRI.
- Designing and managing databases
- Design and developing portals using proprietary and open source content management system including Joomla, Drupal, Wordpress, Kentico, DNN and others.
- Designing software solutions and select technologies and design patterns.

Talentmethods.org

Co-founder and Software Development Expert - 2014 - present

Co-founder of <u>talentmethods.org</u> initiative to help NGOs building their online presence using open-source technologies including Joomla, Drupal, Wordpress and mySQL server and to visualize their data including maps and other data visualization tools.

PMI Lebanon Chapter, Lebanon

Elected Board Member and Director of Administration 2014-Present

- Responsible of the Internal Chapter Administration
- Project Manager of the Lebanon Chapter Business Plan Development Project

- Project Manager of the online presence revamping
- Member of the Digital Media Marketing Committee

Sokin, Congo

Software Developer — 2006–2008

Working as enterprise applications developer at Sokin using open source technologies including JAVA, PHP and MySQL and proprietary technologies including ASP.NET, C#, VB and MS SQL Server.

EDUCATION

2006 Lebanese University - License (4 years) in Computer Sciences

2012 Project Management Professional PMP

2011 Certified Scrum Master, Scrum Arabia, Beirut

CONFERENCES AND TRAININGS

2016 Attended the PMI Leadership Institute Conference, Barcelona

Intensive trainings and workshops about Non-profit leadership and management and soft skills, recruiting volunteers and member acquisition.

2015 Attended the PMI Regional Leadership Meeting, Dubai

Two days workshops about International NGOs, Project Coordination, Non-profit Leadership and Non-profit Business Plans development.

2015 Organized the Second National Project Management Conference, Beirut

I was the project coordinator and member of the steering committee that organized the Second Project Management Conference in Lebanon.

2015 Speaker at the Agile Tour, Beirut

I was speaker at the second version of the international Agile conference in Lebanon about Scrum methodologies and processes.

2014 Speaker about Agile Scrum at AUB, Beirut

2013 Attended ESRI GIS User Conference, Dubai

2012 Attended the First National Project Management Conference, Beirut

2012 Attended ESRI GIS User Conference, Beirut